Kin-iro Mosaic, also known by the abbreviation Kinmoza, is a Japanese 4-panel manga written and illustrated by Yui Hara. The series began serialization in Houbunsha's Manga Time Kirara Max magazine in June 2010 and is licensed in English by Yen Press. An anime television adaptation by Studio Gokumi aired in Japan between July and September 2013, with a second season airing between April and June 2015. An original video animation was released in March 2017. 
Shinobu Omiya is a Japanese high school girl who, five years ago, had a homestay in England with a girl named Alice Cartelet. One day, Shinobu receives a letter from Alice saying she is coming to Japan to live with her. Surely enough, Alice appears and joins Shinobu and her friends Aya Komichi and Yoko Inokuma at her school. She is soon followed by Alice's friend from England, Karen Kujo.
Sinobu Omiya
A graceful, optimistic high school girl, nicknamed Shino by her friends, who previously stayed over at Alice's home in England. She dreams of becoming an interpreter, but generally has bad grades in English, among other subjects. She loves western culture, especially blonde hair. As an airhead, she often misinterprets Alice's advances towards her, but she shows that she loves Alice more than blonde haired girls in serious moments.
Alice Cartelet
A girl from England who transfers into Shinobu's school and lives at her house. She loves Japanese culture but has a complex about her short stature. Alice loves Shinobu, to the point of obsession, and tends to get jealous if she shows interest in others, or if others show interest in her.
Aya Komichi
Shinobu's classmate, who is rather bashful towards Yoko, often not being honest with her feelings. She frequently misinterprets situations between herself and Yoko, responding indignantly and blushing, mostly because of not being able to admit her love to Yoko. She is a smart student, but has a habit of forgetting things, and generally prefers indoor activities.
Yoko Inokuma
Shinobu's classmate and childhood friend since elementary school, who often serves as the tsukkomi character. Cheerful, boyish, and very energetic, she seems to be oblivious of Aya's sentiment towards her, however if she had to choose, she would choose Aya before anyone else. She has two younger siblings: a brother and sister.
Karen Kujo
A half-British, half-Japanese girl who comes from a rich family and was Alice's friend back in England. She also comes to Japan and enrolls in Shinobu's school. She is very energetic, fun-loving and carefree, not even worrying about her grades or her getting fat. She often wears a Union Jack parka jacket over her school uniform and generally speaks in broken Japanese.